

Boston, MA • (508) 565-8116 • patrick.andrew.taylor@gmail.com

### Cloud Architect











Professional Cloud Architect with 10+ years of experience in Information Technology in Financial Services. Skilled in Amazon Web Services, Terraform, Python, and Networking. Strong focus on leadership, team building, and organizational advancement. How can I help?

Contact me

# **Experience**

### Eaton Vance Management, a Morgan Stanley company

Cloud Architect, Core Services • Jan. 2019 — Present

Subject matter expert on all things cloud, leading efforts in architecting, engineering, and operating in AWS.

- Transformed Core Services team from an ad-hoc, collaborative pod to an 11 member Agile team of engineers, while serving as team leader and architect.
- Designed Terraform account vending machine & multi-region landing zone for 60+ AWS accounts across the organization, reducing the lead time on new accounts from multiple days to 1 hour, while ensuring a consistent & compliant environment for each application team.

- Architected & deployed infrastructure for 70+ public websites using infrastructure-as-code and automated deployment pipelines, while shifting responsibility "left" to the development team.
- Designed pull- & push-based logging mechanisms for various AWS logs types to Splunk, eliminating cross-account replication cost & duplicate log retention, with charge back to the application teams.
- Responsible for templatization & design of 150+ module Terraform service catalog, with the goal of shifting "left" of infrastructure-as-code to developers. These include actively-maintained READMEs, semantic versioned releases, and backward compatibility for Terraform & provider version updates.
- Leveraged private & public Route 53 Hosted Zones and AWS Certificate Manager to address growing sprawl & cost of our manual certificate generation & rotation process, reducing lead time by 2 weeks and cost by \$1000+ for each certificate. Developers deploy a single Terraform module to secure & resolve their workloads from on-premises and, if necessary, from the public Internet.
- Modularized our multi-region core networking architecture, including edge web traffic inspection, load balancer sandwiching, and inter- & intra-VPC networking, to ensure a secure network at the edge while also ensuring new accounts can be accessed both onpremises and within AWS with little administrative action.
- Designed, secured, and automated a multi-environment Snowflake organization, to facilitate data sharing between internal and external stakeholders, with disaster recovery and support for multiple regions built in.

### **Eaton Vance Management**

### Network Automation Engineer • Oct. 2017 — Jan. 2019

Focused on automating traditional enterprise networking infrastructure with Python scripting and Ansible playbooking.

- Designed network solutions and maintain service levels across 20 datacenters and remote offices.
- Introduced end-to-end workflow automation via Ansible and Python to infrastructure teams & management.
- Led liaising with engineers & business stakeholders to integrate acquisition networks.
- Drove efforts to standardize network infrastructure, and implement operations training for junior engineers.
- Worked with network visibility vendors to produce single pane-of-glass for identifying network pain points.

### SS&C Technologies

Network Engineer • Oct. 2013 — Oct. 2017

Graduated from part-time site-to-site VPN & firewall administration to full-time design & deployment of resilient networks, serving as primary point-of-contact for 80+ branch office and datacenters.

# **Columbia University**

Various Roles, Columbia University Information Technology (CUIT) • Sept. 2012 — May. 2014

# **General Dynamics**

Intern • May. 2013 — Aug. 2013

# **Providence College**

Various Roles, Providence College Information Technology (PCIT) & Ghana Sustainable Aid Project (GSAP) • Sept. 2010 — Aug. 2012

# Certification

### **Terraform Associate**

Hashicorp • 2020

### **AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate**

Amazon Web Services • 2019

# **Programming with Python**

Codecademy • 2018

# **CCNA Routing & Switching**

Cisco • 2015

### **CCENT**

Cisco • 2015

# **Education**

### **Columbia University**

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering • 2012 — 2014

# **Providence College**

Bachelor of Arts, Pre-Engineering • 2009 — 2012

### **Skills**

#### **Cloud Computing**

I have been interested in cloud computing since 2014, starting by maintaining site-to-site VPNs to AWS. This has evolved to building small serverless microservices, as well as designing logging and modern web architectures. In my latest endeavor, I am the designer & owner of our AWS organizations' account vending machine & landing zone.

#### Team Leadership & Management

My career has evolved from operating as an individual contributor to leading teams of operators, engineers, and architects as part of our Core Services. My ultimate goal is C-suite level management, to deliver large-scale organizational value through modern technology.

#### Open-Source & Closed-Source Development

I make strident efforts to design with open source in mind, whether through development of my own projects or contributions to existing projects. Where closed-source is required, I am avidly documenting specifics to internal wikis, while providing usage instructions for developers to consume these projects effectively.

#### Infrastructure-as-Code

Through the use of Hashicorp Terraform and AWS CloudFormation, I have designed numerous playbooks and modules for many internal consumers, for resources varying from security groups, to common internal architecture patterns, to automated DNS & PKI infrastructure to ensure oneclick security of our web services.

#### **Networking Technologies**

I have worked on various routing architectures, from traditional hub-based networking, to enterprise-grade routing and switching, to application-centric infrastructure, microsegmentation, and software-defined networking.

# **Technologies**

#### **Amazon Web Services**

Backup, Certificate Manager, CloudFormation, CloudFront, CloudWatch Logs, Config, Direct Connect, DynamoDB, EBS, EC2 Auto Scaling, ECR, Elastic Load Balancing v1 & v2, EventBridge, IAM, Kinesis Data Streams & Firehose, KMS, Lambda, PrivateLink, RDS, Route 53, Route 53 Resolver, S3, Security Groups, Secrets Manager, SNS, SQS, Step Functions, Transit Gateway, VPC, WAF

#### Third-Party Cloud Services

Artifactory, Bridgecrew, CloudHealth, Datadog, Prisma, Snowflake, Splunk

#### Infrastructure as Code & Configuration Management

Terraform, CloudFormation, Ansible, Chef

### **Continuous Integration & Continuous Delivery**

Github Actions, GitLab Runner

### **Programming Languages**

Python

### Agile Technologies

Atlassian Jira & Confluence

#### Networking

Cisco, Juniper, Aruba, Palo Alto Networks

# **Personal Projects**

# The Jain-Taylor Family Cookbook

Developer • 2020 — Present

This is a personal project to maintain our family recipes in source control, using Jekyll & Github Pages to render the updated Markdown.

### Resume

Developer • 2021 — Present

This is a personal project to keep my resume up to date, using a combination of Github Actions and Terraform Cloud to build the repository, and using Jekyll & Github Pages to render YAML.

### **Associations**

# **Hack.Diversity**

Mentor • 2021 — PResent

Hack Diversity is a talent provider of Black & Latinx technologists, supporting underrepresented talent with a yearly fellowship, incubator, and other programs. I serve both in a mentor role to Hack fellows, as well as provide educational opportunities related to cloud technologies.

Inspired by <u>@iglovier</u>. Source project can be forked from <u>GitHub</u>.